Who's there?
Geez. Oh God.
SRIKANDI BOARDING HOUSE
Happy Birthday, Kenara Cahyaningrum.
I knew it was just an excuse.
You said you had
an event on campus, right?
Even though you were not on the committee.
Well, what else could I do?
If I went home, Raka would come.
He cheated on you with your best friend,
and he still has no shame.
My poor bestie. She's traumatized
to go home to Jakarta.
And she's traumatized to dance too.
But Nar, the boarding house
is quiet this year.
I was passing through the hallway earlier
and the lights in several rooms were off.
Don't you want to come home with me?
You should know my village.
It's called Kelawangin Village.
I think I've heard the name before.
In the past,
lots of dancers were born there.
But now, it's increasingly rare.
It's better than being here
and being sad about Raka.
What are you saying?
I'm going in. I'm sleepy.
Nar, come with me
to buy souvenirs tomorrow, okay?
-No problem. Bye.
-Bye.
YOU'RE NOT COMING HOME AGAIN THIS YEAR?
HAVE PITY ON YOUR MOTHER
HOW LONG ARE YOU GOING
TO STAY AWAY FROM ME?
I'M NOT WITH LINA ANYMORE
NAR, I MISS YOU
HI. HOW ARE YOU?
IT'S YOUR BIRTHDAY
I WISH YOU HEALTH AND HAPPINESS THERE
KELAWANGIN VILLAGE
HIDDEN GEM ON THE MOUNTAIN SLOPES
DANCE TOURISM IN KELAWANGIN VILLAGE
HAS DROPPED DRASTICALLY
KELAWANGIN VILLAGE GIVES BIRTH
TO MANY TALENTED DANCERS
KELAWANGIN VILLAGE TOURISM HAS BECOME
A POPULAR DESTINATION FOR TOURISTS
IT HAS BEEN ALMOST TEN YEARS
SINCE MAYANG PUTRICANDRA
THE YOUNG DANCER, IS MISSING
Two of these. And bakpia, ma'am.
What flavors are available for the bakpia?
Chocolate…
This one.
One chocolate…
-Ayu, I'm going there.
-Yes.
One chocolate, two cheese.
It's for you, child.
This shawl has chosen its own master.
Whoever is chosen by the shawl
will be bound forever.
That's it, child.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Yu. Look.
-This was given to me.
-By whom?
From the old lady over there,
from the antique shop.
She said this shawl
chose me as its master.
She also gave me this.
Nar, it's really scary.
Don't just accept things from strangers.
-Don't you believe me? Come with me.
-No need. Let's go.
Huh?
FOR RENT
SRIKANDI BOARDING HOUSE
Kelawangin.
Come on. Please, get in.
-Come on. Kelawangin.
-Come here, ma'am! Let's go!
-Come on!
-Ma'am…
We've arrived at Kelawangin.
Come on, Nar. It's raining so hard.
KELAWANGIN VILLAGE
Come on, Nar.
Yes.
-Come on. Let's take shelter.
-What?
Take shelter for now. Come on.
Geez.
It rains so hard.
Nar, just a little bit more.
We're wet anyway.
It's close. It's over there. Come on.
Nar, come on.
Okay.
Come on.
Peace be upon you.
Peace be upon you too.
My daughter's here!
Mom.
Come in, Nar.
This is my friend, Mom.
Her name is Kenar.
Kenar.
Pleasure to meet you, Auntie.
Such a good name.
Why did you go through the rain?
Why didn't you take shelter first?
We were almost here.
It rained when we got off.
Oh dear.
Mom, I brought souvenirs for you and Dad.
You shouldn't have. But thank you.
-My daughter.
-Dad.
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you too.
-You're wet.
-Yes, Dad.
Dad, this is Kenar, my friend.
Kenar, Uncle.
-Okay then. Go take a bath.
-Yes, Dad.
Oh God!
Go take a bath first.
I'll get you some warm water, okay?
-Thank you, Mom.
-Come on, honey.
Come on, Nar.
Come in, Nar.
Geez.
You need a towel? Hang on.
Nar, I'm sorry about
my dad's strange behavior.
You didn't tell them
that you were going to bring a friend?
I did. I told my mother.
She must've told my dad too.
But well… I never bring friends home.
So, I'm the first?
Yes.
None of my high school friends
wanted to come here.
I told you,
I don't have many friends.
Yes?
Ayu, take a bath first.
Come on. I've prepared the water.
Yes, Mom.
-Leave some for me.
-Okay.
What's wrong, honey?
Ayu?
That's not Ayu's room.
Uncle, there was…
Yes, Uncle.
Sorry.
My dad is really annoying.
Never mind you, it's the same with me.
When I was in high school,
I wasn't allowed to date.
He said I was still a kid.
Now that I'm in college,
I'm still not allowed.
He has a point, Yu.
I regret ever dating.
In the end, I was hurt.
At least you had fun because you knew
what it was like to fall in love.
But no one is ready to lose someone,
especially in a painful way.
So, maybe your father
doesn't want you to be hurt like me.
So, you're not allowed to date.
Anyway,
I can see that your father's
actually a good person.
Am I right?
Yu.
She fell asleep.
Oh no… Low battery.
Whoever is chosen by the shawl
will be bound forever.
Gross.
Oh God.
Uncle…
I came to the kitchen to get a bucket.
Ayu's room is leaking, Uncle.
Excuse me, Uncle.
Until death separates you.
Mom.
I'm going to take Kenar for a walk.
Okay then.
-Take care.
-Okay.
Hey.
Because you're a dancer,
I want to take you to a dance studio here.
-Why?
-Child…
Hello, sir.
You have a problem with the cheating guy,
not the dancer.
But still, he cheated with a dancer.
It's not related.
-Ms. Ayu.
-Yes, ma'am.
Nar, come on.
LARAS BUDOYO DANCE STUDIO
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you too.
-Hi.
-Ms. Ayu.
How are you?
I'm good, Yu.
This is my friend from Jakarta.
Her name is Kenar.
Ma'am.
Kenar.
This is Madam Sarti,
a teacher at this dance studio.
This is Dirjo, the Saron player,
the idol of the girls here.
-Dirjo.
-Kenar.
Do you miss it?
Huh?
-What?
-Do you miss dancing?
Forward.
Dirjo can't stop looking at you.
He's smiling.
Come here.
Madam, my friend here
is a dancer, you know.
-Ask her to dance.
-Ayu.
Madam…
-She's a dancer.
-Ayu.
-Nar, let's dance.
-Yes, teach me.
-Please dance!
-Let's dance!
Let's dance.
-Okay…
-Yes, teach us some moves.
I haven't danced for a long time.
I've forgotten. Sorry.
Enough. Let's get back to dancing.
Come on.
There.
I have a feeling
that Banyu is here now.
Who will be his victim now?
Honey.
I'm still not sure…
that Banyu had something to do
with Mayang's death ten years ago.
What do you mean?
Banyu had no grudge against that girl.
Honey.
You knew Banyu well, right?
So, Dirjo's uncle
is a well-known guy here.
He made this village prosperous.
But I feel sorry for Dirjo.
Kenar?
Are you even here?
What did you say?
What did you talk about?
Dirjo's parents have died.
And his sister is missing.
They still haven't found her.
How come?
I'm going to sleep.
Who are you?
Stop! Help!
Go away!
Come with me.
Ayu.
Yu. Wake up, Yu.
Yu, wake up.
Actually, this isn't the first time
I've seen that figure.
She has been in my dreams before.
And…
there was a black figure.
A really scary figure.
Actually, I don't want to tell this story.
What story?
I don't know if this is related or not.
I heard the story from other people.
My parents never told me anything.
That room in my house
was my uncle's.
My dad's younger brother.
His name was Banyu.
Dad never let anyone into that room.
Even my mother.
He…
had a girlfriend.
A dancer.
Her name was Ratih Mahyu.
She lived in this village too.
My uncle died
because he was burned alive
by the villagers.
My father also restricts me
from socializing with the people here.
That's why I've been
out of town since high school.
But people believe
that every ten years…
he will ask for a sacrifice.
Another dancer.
And when I was little,
there was already one victim.
She disappeared until now.
Dirja's younger sister.
Mayang once told me
that Ratih Mahyu often visited her.
Ratih Mahyu is an extension of Banyu
to take revenge on the people here.
That's why every ten years,
my uncle always holds a closed ritual
to appease Banyu's spirit.
Wait a minute.
So, are you saying
that Kenar should meet Uncle Adi
to discuss this?
No need. It's okay. I'm bothering you.
Actually, I'm okay.
I'm just confused.
What does all this have to do with me?
Ayu.
You must be thinking
about your dad and my uncle, right?
My dad surely doesn't want to have
anything to do with Uncle Adi.
Yes, I know.
For now…
this is all I can tell you.
If she asks you to dance,
don't do it.
Fight her.
Have a drink, honey.
Where is she?
Dancer.
Honey?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Open.
Where am I?
Why is it locked?
Open!
-Open!
-Calm down.
TWIN ECLIPSE
TWO SOULS, ONE LOVE, ONE REVENGE
NARIK SUKMO
Dance.
No.
No!
Stop!
Help!
Dance.
Kenar?
Kenar!
Mom, Kenar…
Kenar?
Dad, open it quickly!
-Nar. Open, Kenar!
-Kenar!
Kenar.
Kenar?
Dad. Hurry, Dad.
Kenar. Dad, come on. Hurry, Dad.
-What has been buried…
-Kenar!
Kenar.
-…will rise.
-Kenar!
Kenar.
-Kenar.
-Open, Kenar.
Help!
Kenar!
Pawned soul
-is asking for
-Kenar!
a ransom.
-Love, death
-Kenar!
-will demand
one of the nights.
-Kenar!
-Just break it, Dad.
No flowers.
Kenar!
-Kenar!
-Child!
-Child?
-Child.
-Kenar!
Child.
Ayu!
What time is it now?
I'm just scared
something will happen to you.
What will happen, Dad?
What's actually going on?
Dad. What's actually
going on with our family?
You never tell me anything.
-Suddenly, my friend flew like that.
-I don't understand either!
You're lying!
Enough!
Ayu!
Yu… Where's Kenar?
You said that my uncle and Ratih Mahyu
have a grudge
against the villagers, right?
So, why is Kenar affected?
She doesn't come from here.
What happened?
What's going on, Yu?
I want to bring Kenar back to Yogya.
It's no longer safe here.
How is it not safe?
I don't want Kenar
to have the same fate as Mayang.
Auntie…
Thank you, Auntie, Uncle.
Take good care of yourself, okay?
It's okay.
Let's go.
Are you okay, Nar?
I'm okay.
-I'm sorry. If I didn't bring you here…
-It's okay, Yu.
This is not your fault.
Gotcha!
Kenar. Calm down, okay?
-No. Shut up. Where's Ayu?
-I can explain.
Where's Ayu?
You were thrown away
by Mr. Prastomo's people.
That's why I brought you here now.
Impossible. Lies!
-No.
-I can't possibly…
-Why would I lie to you?
-So, where's Ayu?
I don't know where Ayu is.
Maybe she got affected
by his father's story.
How do you know Ayu's father
sent those people?
I'm from here, Kenar.
Of course I know.
In Dewa Kelawangin, there are two groups.
Mr. Prastomo's group and my uncle's group.
This is my sister's room, Mayang.
Calm yourself for now, okay?
Tonight, I'll take you to the terminal
to return to Yogya.
Jo…
You have to be able to convince the girl.
Kenar, right?
She's here already anyway.
Don't fail.
Yes, Uncle.
But what about Ayu, Uncle?
As for Ayu, that's my business.
After Kenar regains consciousness,
after she wakes up,
we have to carry out
the ritual immediately.
Keep it from running away.
Can you?
Drink first, Yu.
Mom…
I want to look for Kenar, okay?
Do it later.
Mom…
Where is she?
Later. You're still weak.
Hopefully, Kenar is fine.
-Honey.
-Mom…
Dad. Where's Kenar? Have you found her?
Not yet.
Nobody saw her.
But I've asked my people
to look for her. Okay?
Okay then.
Go away!
Help! Go away!
-Ayu. I'm your father.
-Help!
Ayu, I'm your dad. I'm your father!
Dad.
There was a black figure.
-I saw a black figure.
-Calm down, okay?
Calm down.
You calm down.
Ayu…
Calm down, child. Ayu.
Calm down, okay?
Okay.
I'm here, Yu. I'm here.
Who are you?
What do you want, little brother?
BANYU CIPTO, SON OF TJOKRO SUDJIWO
Is this still about your grudge
from 20 years ago?
Tell me,
your big brother.
Let me avenge it.
But…
Don't hurt Ayu.
Not Ayu.
She's your girl too.
Your niece.
Please.
Go home.
Banyu.
Come out, all of you.
It's me.
Stand up!
Tonight, we carry out the ritual.
I've found the dancer.
Stop! Don't bother me. Stop!
Let me go.
Let me go!
The time has come.
No.
Kenar?
Are you okay?
Bring the dancer here.
Yes, sir.
Kelawangin was prosperous
since Mr. Prastomo
and Banyu's family came here.
Mr. Prastomo and Banyu
often shared their harvest
with the villagers.
But one day, the villagers fell ill.
Some even died.
After an investigation,
it was because of the harvest
given by Mr. Prastomo and Banyu.
Angry villagers
brought Banyu to the field.
Let's go!
-Come on!
-Bring him!
Let me go!
-It wasn't me!
-Move!
Take him!
My uncle tried to stop it.
But he was ignored.
-Not me!
-Burn him!
-No!
-Take him there!
-Hold him!
-Come on!
No!
Let me go!
Let's punish him!
-Finish him!
Get him!
Let's get him!
Come on!
Come on! Get him!
Help!
-I didn't see it,
-Help!
but they said Banyu was burned.
Go!
Since then, Mr. Prastomo's family
withdrew themselves from the community.
And strange events
began to occur in the village.
There's a supernatural being
that is rumored to be Banyu.
Your sister was one of the victims?
And…
Ratih Mahyu…
She was his girlfriend, right?
Since then, Ratih Mahyu
has disappeared from the village.
She hanged herself.
My uncle was heartbroken.
Because they said
my uncle loved Ratih Mahyu.
-Ayu.
-Honey!
-Ayu! Honey, water.
Ayu.
Ayu!
Go away.
Go away, Banyu!
-Ayu.
-Child.
Ayu.
-Ayu.
Okay.
It's okay.
Honey.
What do you want, brother?
What?
Is this your doing?
Ratih Mahyu?
I've been silent for 20 years.
We both know what happened
and who is responsible for all of this.
Ratih asked me to be quiet,
without having to avenge anything,
and I obey!
I obey!
But what's going on?
What's going on?
Ayu…
My only child…
You hurt her!
How could you, brother?
How could you?
Come on out! Come out!
TWIN ECLIPSE
Twin eclipse.
Two souls.
One love.
One revenge.
Narik Sukmo.
Dancer.
What is it?
My uncle is holding a ritual
to appease the spirits
of Banyu and Ratih Mahyu.
We have to go to the dance studio now.
Me too?
Yes.
And where is Ayu?
Ayu…
Ayu should be there.
She's waiting for you.
Honey.
Where are you going?
I know where Kenar is.
Where is she?
Just stay at home, okay?
Close the doors and windows tightly.
Wait for me to come home.
-What's going on?
-Calm down.
Banyu isn't the culprit.
Not my brother.
Banyu and Ratih Mahyu
is using the girl to take revenge.
Honey. It's time.
It's time.
Honey…
I'll leave Ayu with you, okay?
-Why are you saying that?
-Calm down.
Calm down.
Okay?
Please tell Ayu
that I'm sorry, okay?
Honey…
-Be careful.
-Okay.
Okay? I'll take my leave.
Dirja?
Help!
-Help! Let me go!
-Bring him!
-Come on!
-Take him!
I'm not the culprit!
Let's go!
-Help!
-Go!
Let me go!
Help!
-Come on!
-Help!
-Let me go!
-Go!
You have no shame!
Come here!
Forgive me.
Don't do it again.
You have no shame.
Forgive me.
Not me.
It's not our fault.
Die!
-Burn him!
-Come on!
-Go!
-Let him burn!
-Help!
-Burn him!
-Don't burn me!
-Let him burn!
-Burn him!
-Damn you!
-I'll burn you!
-Burn him!
-Let's go!
-Don't burn me.
-Burn.
-Burn him! Just kill him! Burn!
-Burn!
-Bastard! He's a traitor!
-A traitor!
-Burn him!
-Help!
-Just let him burn!
Die!
Take that!
-Come on!
-Burn!
-Yeah!
-Burn him!
Kenar.
Let's go.
Ready?
Ready…
Ready for what?
Okay.
You will lie down there.
Me?
Yes.
Calm down, okay? Come on.
It's okay.
You sit here.
-Kenar. Run, Kenar.
-Shut up!
What do you want?
Kenar. Run!
-Run!
-Hey, Kenar!
Kenar!
Don't let her get away!
Stop!
Run!
Let me go.
Hey! Stop!
Huh?
-Where is she?
-I don't know.
Where are you, child?
Sir…
I think she's over there.
Really?
Yes.
Tonight is the night of death.
One life is ready to be offered.
Tonight is the night of life.
A thousand lives to save.
Tonight is the night of death.
One life is ready to be offered.
Tonight is the night of life.
A thousand lives to save.
Tonight is the night of death.
-One life is ready to be offered.
-Let me go.
-Tonight is the night of life.
-Help!
-Kenar!
-A thousand lives to save.
Let me go.
Kenar, run!
Help.
You're outrageous, Adi.
No…
I've been silent all this time.
You think I don't know
that you were the one who slandered Banyu
and me?
Banyu wasn't a bad person!
He protected the villagers.
He always cared for your children.
Banyu did nothing wrong!
Adi is the one who deserves to die.
He poisoned the villagers.
And you, Dirja.
Yes, you!
How could you, Dirja?
You let all this happen.
You don't have a heart.
You let your sister die
because of this curse ritual.
Prastomo!
Enough.
Damn you!
You will meet your brother.
No!
Let me go.
No.
Carry on.
-Tonight is the night of death.
-Let me go, please.
-One life is ready to be offered.
-Please let me go.
Tonight is the night of life.
A thousand lives to save.
Tonight is the night of death.
We pay our respects to our ancestors.
The time has come.
Come…
and party with me.
I ask for protection,
and I will serve you.
On this night of death,
one life has been prepared.
Tonight is the night of life.
A thousand lives to save.
Kenar.
Dance!
Kenar!
Please!
Dance!
Dance.
Narik Sukmo.
Stop dancing!
You dare to fight me?
Come on!
Help!
Thank you, Kenar.
You've helped us.
Dance. Don't stop.
Kenar.
Hey, wake up.
Wake up, Kenar.
Get up.
Kenar.
You…
Uncle…
Uncle. Hang on, Uncle.
Hey…
-Uncle…
-Take care of Ayu for me.
No, Uncle.
Uncle, I beg you.
-There's nothing
-Uncle…
that she needs to be afraid of now.
No…
It's all…
No!
No.
Uncle. No, Uncle.
No!
PRASTOMO, SON OF TJOKRO SUDJIWO
BORN: 2/6/1976 - DIED: 11/4/2024
Let's go, Mom.
The hatred was born
because Mr. Adicandra
secretly liked Ratih Mahyu.
The villagers had the heart
to parade Banyu.
A 20-year grudge.
Because they, Ratih Mahyu and Banyu…
were separated
without them having
the chance to be together.
KELAWANGIN VILLAGE
Kenar, come on. Hurry up.
Yes, I'm coming!
Wait… Dirja.
Where are you going?
She's asking a question.
Get a little closer.
I'm planning to go to Yogya.
There's no one else here for me,
so why should I be here?
So…
who do you have in Yogya?
A future I'm looking for.
Gosh, a future!
Hey, let's go.